<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Martín Quesada Zaragoza</title><link>https://martnquesada.github.io/categories/</link><description>Latest blog posts from Martín Quesada Zaragoza</description><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 22:48:29 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://martnquesada.github.io/categories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Taking a look at (some) tokenizers</title><link>https://martnquesada.github.io/blog/2023/05/taking-a-look-at-some-tokenizers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martnquesada.github.io/blog/2023/05/taking-a-look-at-some-tokenizers/</guid><description>Recently I have been working on writing a tokenizer from scratch in Rust. In the process, I wanted to really understand the implementation of some commonly used tokenizers. Fun, I know.
Moses Tokenizer Webpage<a href="http://www2.statmt.org/">http://www2.statmt.org/</a> and the implementation that I’ll talk about tokenizer.perl.
If you already know Moses, you know. Silent nod. For everyone else, Moses is an NLP framework written in Perl, focused on statistical machine translation. It is super easy to install anywhere and everyone loves it because of it.</description></item><item><title>An unhelpful summary of AMTA 2022</title><link>https://martnquesada.github.io/blog/2022/11/an-unhelpful-summary-of-amta-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martnquesada.github.io/blog/2022/11/an-unhelpful-summary-of-amta-2022/</guid><description>Last September I attended virtually the 15th biennial conference of the Association for Machine Translation in the Americas, A.K.A. AMTA 2022. There I presented an adaptation of my master’s thesis in collaboration with my tutor (shameless self-promotion here). Even though at the moment I am not enrolled in any course, he helped me with several revisions and provided the budget for attendance, so I wanted to thank him before I move on.</description></item><item><title>Things I have read (I)</title><link>https://martnquesada.github.io/blog/2021/11/things-i-have-read-i/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 11:21:24 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://martnquesada.github.io/blog/2021/11/things-i-have-read-i/</guid><description>This is the first of a series of posts where I’ll write some impressions on the latest books that I have read. It started as a personal log, but since I tend to read a ton of book reviews and they are my main way of discovering new stuff, I reckon that someone who reads it may also get something out of it.
The Grownup I’m currently in Seoul for a while, and my choices for new stuff to read are limited to second-hand bookstores that have an English section, so not much reading in Spanish will be done until I am back home.</description></item></channel></rss>